Sreejith Balakrishnan, Ph.D. Candidate, National University of Singapore

Singapore, +6597262108, sreejithb@gmail.com

LINKS	Homepage, Google Scholar, LinkedIn				
PROFILE	I am a PhD candidate interested in developing Artificial Intelligence driven decision-making algorithms that happlications in robotics with a focus on value alignment and fairness. My current research topics include va alignment through Inverse Reinforcement Learning and fairness in Reinforcement Learning. In addition to experience as a researcher, I also have an industry career of 8 years. I have held many positions, including Reseating Engineer at the Singapore Management University and Section Manager at ABB Private Limited.				
RESEARCH INTERESTS	Inverse Reinforcement Learning				
	Deep Learning				
	Robotics				
	Fairness in algorithmic-decision making				
	Causal inference				
PUBLICATIONS					
Dec 2020	Sreejith Balakrishnan , Quoc Phong Nguyen, Bryan Kian Hsiang Low, and Harold Soh. Efficient Exploration of Reward Functions in Inverse Reinforcement Learning via Bayesian Optimization. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2020.				
Aug 2022	Sreejith Balakrishnan , Jianxin Bi, and Harold Soh. SCALES: From Fairness Principles to Constrained Decision-Making. Artificial Intelligence, Ethics, and Society (AIES) 2022.				
AWARDS					
Jan 2021	Research Achievement Award, National University of Singapore				
	Awarded for the NeurIPS 2020 accepted paper.				
Jan 2019	Honor List of Student Tutors, National University of Singapore				
	Awarded for outstanding tutoring for the module "AI Decision Making and Planning"				
Aug 2016 — Jul 2020	NUS Research Scholarship, National University of Singapore				
	Awarded to pursue Ph.D. program in School of Computing at National University of singapore.				
EDUCATION					
Aug 2016 — Present	Ph.D., National University of Singapore	Singapore			
	 Working on Inverse Reinforcement Learning and Value Alignment for robotics as well as Fa Decision Making. Relevant coursework: Uncertainty Modelling in AI, Advanced Topics in Artificial Intellige 				
Aug 2010 — Jul 2013	Master of Science, National University of Singapore	Singapore			
	M.Sc in Electrical Engineering with a specialization in Computer Engineering	-			
	 4.6 GPA Relevant coursework: Real-time Systems, Linear Systems, Pattern Recognition, Evolutionary Computing 				
Aug 2004 — Jul 2008	Bachelor of Engineering, Nanyang Technological University	Singapore			
	 B.Eng in Electrical and Electronics Engineering with a Minor in Computing First Class Honors Relevant coursework: Robotics & Automation, Control Engineering Design, Modelling & Computer Vision 	control,			

MACHINE LEARNING SKILLS	Inverse Reinforcement Learning	Expert	Deep Learning	Expert	
	Algorithmic Decision-making	Expert	Reinforcement Learning	Expert	
	Gaussian Process Regression	Expert	Active Learning	Experienced	
	Bayesian Optimization	Expert	Evolutionary Algorithms	Skillful	
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY					
Aug 2020 — Present	Research Assistant, National University of Singapore			Singapore	
	 Assist with research projects under the CLeAR Lab in NUS. Manage the server environments required for the various projects. Assist with procurement of hardware and software components necessary for upcoming 			ing projects.	
Aug 2017 — Dec 2017	Teaching Assistant, AI Planning and Decision Making, School of Computing, NUS, Singapore			Singapore	
	 Conducted tutorials for the undergraduate (4th year) module Awarded Honor List of Student Tutors Received a high rating of 4.4 out of 5 based on student feedback. 				
Mar 2015 — Jul 2016	Research Engineer and Project Lead, School of Information Systems, SMU, Singapore				
	 Technical lead for a Singapore urban planning project undertaken by Fujitsu-SMU Urban Computing & Engineering Corporate Lab (UNiCEN). Modeled the passenger flow at various taxi stands in Singapore to address the mismatch in taxi supply and demand. 				
Jun 2008 — Feb 2015	Section Manager, Regional Afte Limited, Singapore	er Sales Supp	ort, ABB Private	Singapore	
	 Spearheaded a team of 5 engineers to provide engineering solutions to customers in Asia, Australia, and New Zealand. Invited to conduct advanced-level product training for engineers and customers in various countries around the globe. 				
PROJECTS					
Jun 2019 — Dec 2019	Decentralized Task Allocation for Multi-robot Systems, National University of Singapore				
	• Designed a task allocation algorithm for a decentralized multi-robot environment with limited communication.				
Aug 2007 — Jul 2008	Control System for Humanoid Robot, Final Year Project, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore				
	 Interfaced a humanoid robot with sensors using various communication protocols like Bluetooth and I2C. 				
Jul 2007 — Dec 2007	Humanoid Robot Exhibition, Discovery Center, Singapore				
	 Led a team of 12 students to creat synchronized against background 		bition where the movements of 4 hu	manoid robots were	
PROGRAMMING					
	Python for machine learning (Highly	y Proficient)			
	Python for machine learning (Highly R for data analytics and visualisation				
PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES		n (Proficient)			

C/C++/C# for robotics (Working Knowledge)